<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Trevor Dixon]]></title>
	<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2013-10-08T11:54:18-06:00</updated>
	<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Trevor Dixon]]></name>
		<email><![CDATA[trevordixon@gmail.com]]></email>
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans Would Rather Cut Your Baby in Half Than Provide Healthcare to Poor People]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/government-shutdown/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-08T11:55:00-06:00</updated>
		<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/government-shutdown</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Republican lawmakers remind me of the conniving young mother who sought to persuade wise King Solomon that she was the actual mother of the disputed infant, but who shrugged at the proposed bisection of the tot. Democratic and Republican congresspeople argue with equal vigor that the other party is responsible for the shutdown, but out of the other side of their mouths, Republicans mutter <em>it&rsquo;s not even that bad</em>, betraying their guilt. If Republicans truly believed that President Obama and the Democrats caused the shutdown, they wouldn&rsquo;t try to downplay its gravity.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Sustenance]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/sustenance/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-03T10:16:00-06:00</updated>
		<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/sustenance</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>To &ldquo;sustain&rdquo; somebody doesn&rsquo;t mean to agree with or pledge loyalty to that person. Sustenance is provided in doing things that uplift or encourage or otherwise help. Feeling or publicly expressing allegiance to President Monson does so little to sustain him; instead, help him to accomplish his mission. President Monson worries about many things and has many goals. Alleviate his worries and advance his goals by serving neighbors and uplifting the elderly and lonely.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Will a Robot Steal Your Job?]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/will-a-robot-steal-your-job/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-01T10:12:00-06:00</updated>
		<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/will-a-robot-steal-your-job</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>No! A robot will <em>do</em> your job <em>for you</em>. Job automation might primarily benefit employers in the short term, putting workers in direct competition with robots and some employees out of work, but ultimately, an automatic economy will liberate humans. Don&rsquo;t fear unemployment; look forward to free time! Job automation will benefit everybody if the vast wealth generated by robots is shared.</p>

<p>Inspired by <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2013/09/27/researchers_claim_many_jobs_at_risk_for_automation_here_s_what_they_missed.html">What Undercover Boss and The Jetsons Tell Us About the Future of Jobs</a>.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone's New Fingerprint Scanner Circumvented in One Day]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/iphones-new-fingerprint-scanner-circumvented/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-23T22:42:00-06:00</updated>
		<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/iphones-new-fingerprint-scanner-circumvented</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The day after the release of the iPhone 5s, a team of German hackers had <a href="http://www.ccc.de/en/updates/2013/ccc-breaks-apple-touchid">circumvented the iPhone&rsquo;s fingerprint scanner</a> causing many to dismiss TouchID as insecure and useless. I&rsquo;m more forgiving. In Hollywood, fingerprint scanners represent military-grade security, but to hold them to such standards in real life is unfair. TouchID is a consumer product that does well to balance security and usability; it isn&rsquo;t the panacea for all security issues, but given that <a href="http://www.sophos.com/en-us/press-office/press-releases/2011/08/67-percent-of-consumers-do-not-have-password-protection-on-their-mobile-phones.aspx">two-thirds of mobile phone users currently employ <em>no</em> access restriction tools</a>, easy-to-use smartphone security mechanisms like TouchID will improve security generally.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Know]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/09/11/I-dont-know/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-11T21:09:00-06:00</updated>
		<id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/09/11/I-dont-know</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Dr. Knutson tells us that in recent years, he has decided to be decisive, but in a recording of an interview with Jon Dupre, the guest expert Dr. Knutson exhibits a rare and refreshing <em>irresoluteness</em>. Pressed to take a stand on tough issues, Dr. Knutson declines to deliver convenient common-sense opinions, offering instead a wise, humble &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know&rdquo;. So-called common sense (a trait people tend to claim exclusively for themselves and those of like mind) produces so many wrong answers. The world needs more people with the patience and thoughtfulness to speak in less than absolute terms and the guts to say &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
