<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CS 404 | Trevor Dixon]]></title>
  <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/categories/cs-404/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-03T12:59:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Trevor Dixon]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[trevordixon@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Squander Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/12/03/dont-squander-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-03T09:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/12/03/dont-squander-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In reading about and considering the plight of those addicted to video games and lost in virtual worlds, I sometimes take false comfort in comparing my relatively minor weaknesses to such wild addictions. Few of us abuse technology in such an unhealthy manner as to approach the level of addiction, but to invest in television, video games, social media, or frivolous internet surfing for even a couple of hours each day requires the sacrifice of equally enjoyable but far more valuable pursuits. I believe that committing to more than one TV show and making time for more than one movie per week represents too much media consumption. In my experience, the time saved by consciously limiting entertainment is time I spend playing with my daughter or programming side projects—activities I&rsquo;m much more proud of.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software Shouldn't Be Patentable]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/software-shouldnt-be-patentable/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T23:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/software-shouldnt-be-patentable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="840" height="630" src="http://trevordixon.github.io//www.youtube.com/embed/KDpPkmNSpQM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacking Isn't Cute]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/hacking-isnt-cute/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T23:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/hacking-isnt-cute</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I reflect on <em>Ghost in the Wires</em>, the memoir of famous hacker Kevin Mitnick, I&rsquo;m disgusted by Mitnick&rsquo;s selfish disregard for others. Mitnick&rsquo;s thesis is that his hacks amounted to harmless games and that he was the victim of unjust persecution by brutish thugs from big corporations and the government. Mitnick never physically harmed anybody and never profited from his hacks, but his actions seriously wounded civil society&rsquo;s trust.</p>

<p>If we all had to deal regularly with liars like Kevin Mitnick, it would rock the foundations of society. Many social constructs are built on a foundation of trust, and they continue to stand, because most people are trustworthy. Liars that abuse that trust do real harm to those constructs. If everybody lied like Kevin Mitnick, sociality would become dangerous, and the joy of human interaction would be lost. Life would be miserable.</p>

<p>Kevin Mitnick now leads an honorable life, but the idea promoted in his memoir—that hacking and lying are a fun game for those cut out for it—is a dangerous attitude.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teach Programming to Junior High Students to Get More Women in Computer Science]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/teach-programming-to-girls-in-junior-high/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T13:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/teach-programming-to-girls-in-junior-high</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Exposing teenagers to computer science leads, not uncommonly, to a love affair with programming. Unfortunately, due to cultural influences, girls are far less likely to be exposed to programming by their peers. Computer science should be introduced to every junior high school student. Ensuring so would particularly benefit girls, who are less likely to discover the joy of programming outside of school.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Everything]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/12/open-source-everything/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-12T10:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/11/12/open-source-everything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Open source software is born, evolved, and maintained in the same way the whole economy of Zion will be. Open source development will work just as well for book authoring, scientific research, city planning, art, and many other disciplines as it does for software development. We&rsquo;ll benefit enormously if leaders in other fields adopt open source development like the software community has.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
