<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CS 404 | Trevor Dixon]]></title>
  <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/categories/cs-404/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-31T11:45:18-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Trevor Dixon]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[trevordixon@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crippled Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/31/a-crippled-internet/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-31T10:55:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/31/a-crippled-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To grant companies, ISPs, or the government the power to censor Internet content undermines the principles that made the Internet great and threatens to diminish the Internet&rsquo;s power for good. The unregulated internet we are accustomed to won out over another vision for the World Wide Web: a tightly controlled, <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2013/05/01/180255276/the-single-most-valuable-document-in-the-history-of-the-world-wide-web">&ldquo;government-sponsored broadband network that would have delivered video from TV stations and other approved content&rdquo;</a>—another FCC-regulated medium like radio or television. Such an internet might have been useless for pirating copyrighted material, distributing pornography, or bullying teenagers, but neither would it have facilitated an Arab Spring or inspired a generation of entrepreneurs. The properties of the World Wide Web that make it so dangerous are the same properties that make it a tool for incredible good. To control the Internet is to cripple it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Security is an Afterthought]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/17/security-is-an-afterthought/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-17T10:28:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/17/security-is-an-afterthought</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thirty years ago, it was already clear to network managers like Clifford Stoll that the username/password method of authentication is faulty. (People tend to pick easy-to-remember passwords that are easy to guess; complex assigned passwords get written down and are easily stolen.) Given that so many other aspects of computing have evolved dramatically after all these years, it&rsquo;s remarkable that this model is the still the norm.</p>

<p>Because our authentication methods are the same as they were 30 years ago, many of Clifford Stoll&rsquo;s hacker&rsquo;s break-in tactics work just as well against today&rsquo;s networks as they did in the 80s. At least our intolerance for this kind of hacking has caught up with the risks! Such an intrusion would not be taken so lightly by today&rsquo;s network managers as it was by those Stoll elicited for support.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans Would Rather Cut Your Baby in Half Than Provide Healthcare to Poor People]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/government-shutdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-08T11:55:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/government-shutdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Republican lawmakers remind me of the conniving young mother who sought to persuade wise King Solomon that she was the actual mother of the disputed infant, but who shrugged at the proposed bisection of the tot. Democratic and Republican congresspeople argue with equal vigor that the other party is responsible for the shutdown, but out of the other side of their mouths, Republicans mutter <em>it&rsquo;s not even that bad</em>, betraying their guilt. If Republicans truly believed that President Obama and the Democrats caused the shutdown, they wouldn&rsquo;t try to downplay its gravity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sustenance]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/sustenance/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-03T10:16:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/sustenance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To &ldquo;sustain&rdquo; somebody doesn&rsquo;t mean to agree with or pledge loyalty to that person. Sustenance is provided in doing things that uplift or encourage or otherwise help. Feeling or publicly expressing allegiance to President Monson does so little to sustain him; instead, help him to accomplish his mission. President Monson worries about many things and has many goals. Alleviate his worries and advance his goals by serving neighbors and uplifting the elderly and lonely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will a Robot Steal Your Job?]]></title>
    <link href="http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/will-a-robot-steal-your-job/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T10:12:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://trevordixon.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/will-a-robot-steal-your-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No! A robot will <em>do</em> your job <em>for you</em>. Job automation might primarily benefit employers in the short term, putting workers in direct competition with robots and some employees out of work, but ultimately, an automatic economy will liberate humans. Don&rsquo;t fear unemployment; look forward to free time! Job automation will benefit everybody if the vast wealth generated by robots is shared.</p>

<p>Inspired by <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2013/09/27/researchers_claim_many_jobs_at_risk_for_automation_here_s_what_they_missed.html">What Undercover Boss and The Jetsons Tell Us About the Future of Jobs</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
